♪〜
〜♪
（銃声）
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
最初に銃を手にしたんは—
I first picked up a gun
at the age of seven.
七(なな)つのときやった
And I fired it.
撃ったのもそうや
I remember that the trigger
was strangely easy to pull.
引き金が異様なほど
軽かったのを覚えとる
笑(わろ)たわ
I laughed.
I laughed because that one shot
had silenced the sickening trash...
親代わりなんちゅう
肩書つけとる胸クソ悪いクズが—
...who had titled himself
my guardian.
１発で しゃべらんように
なったんやから
It was that simple.
ホンマ 簡単なもんやで
And so, I was free.
これで自由になった
Yes, tomorrow, things
would be different...
あしたになったら
なんかが変わる
...tomorrow.
あしたになったら…
けどな—
But things always go
from bad to worse.
状況は 悪いほうばっかりに
転がりよる
I can't escape.
泥沼や
（チャペル･ザ･エバーグリーン）
人生は 絶え間なく連続した
問題集と同じだ
Life is like an incessant
series of problems...
... all difficult, with
brutally limited choices...
そろって複雑 選択肢は極小—
... and a time limit.
加えて 時間制限がある
The worst thing is
to make no decision...
一番 最低なのは—
夢のような解決を待って
何一つ選ばないことだ
... waiting for the ideal
conclusion to present itself.
Make the best choice
in a split-second.
最良の方法を瞬時に選べ
We're not like God.
Not only are our powers limited...
私たちは神とは違う
万能でないだけ
鬼になる必要がある
... but we sometimes
have to play the Devil.
I didn't want other kids
to grow up like me...
（ウルフウッド）
自分みたいな人間にしたら
あかん思て—
...so I started up
an orphanage.
孤児院のまね事を始めた
It gave my life meaning.
張り合い出たわ
I was doing things
for the good of others.
自分のやることが
人のためになっとるんや
It was my little
bit of happiness.
ささやかな幸せっちゅう
やつやな
（銃声）
But sometimes,
I still think...
（ウルフウッド）
けどな やっぱり思うで
...this planet is the worst.
この星は最悪や
It's a horrible planet.
最悪の星や
（吹きすさぶ風の音）
（銃声）
What do you find so amusing
about this, Knives?
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
こんなことして 何が楽しいんだ
ナイヴズ
Nuts. It's full of soot.
（ウルフウッド）
あかん ススだらけや
フーッ
He wasn't going to shoot me!
（ヴァッシュ）
あの子に撃つ気はなかった
Please... please don't
look at me like that!
（ウルフウッド）頼むから
そんな目で見んといてくれ
Think of the circumstances.
事情っちゅうもんが
あるやんか
あっ
ぐっ…
くっ
んっ…
うっ
You still need work.
まだまだ だな
Every moment hesitated
is a moment gone of life.
“躊躇(ちゅうちょ)すれば その時間だけ
命がすり減る”
I'm sure I taught you that.
そう教えたはずだが
Why are you here?
なんで ここに…
Have you lost some
weight, Nicholas?
少しやつれたか？ ニコラス
I was traveling
with a real troublemaker.
難儀なやつと
旅しとったさかいな
Conflicting worries
are not good. Kill him.
心労を重ねるのはよくない
あの男を殺せ
うっ… けど—
But Knives told me
to bring him!
わいは“あの男を連れてこい”と
ナイヴズに言われとる
That order has been retracted.
その依頼は撤回された
Then, the money...
（ウルフウッド）ほんなら 金は？
You will be paid,
as promised.
無論 予定どおり支払われる
I also guarantee the lives
of the kids in December...
ディセムバにいる
ガキどもの命も保証しよう
...upon the name of Chapel the Evergreen
of the Gung-ho Guns.
ガンホーガンズの—
チャペル･ザ･エバーグリーンの
名において
And as of now...
そして—
今から お前もガンホーガンズだ
...you too, are
a Gung-ho Gun.
Deal with the situation...
（チャペル）状況に対応しろ
そして 私の持つ称号を
受け継ぐんだ
... and then, inherit my title.
（ヴァッシュ）あっ
（ウルフウッド）んっ…
くっ
あっ…
His expression...
（ウルフウッド）
なんちゅうツラしとんねん
He's acting like
he killed the kid.
人殺したんは
まるで自分みたいやんか
Blame me if you blame me.
Hit me if I need hitting!
責めるんやったら責めい
殴ってでも
わいを なじってみい
Then, I'll...
そしたら わいは…
Mr. Priest?
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
牧師さん？
あっ いたんですね よかった
Oh, good!
You are here!
Meryl and I made you some sandwiches.
Please eat them, if you like.
先輩と
サンドイッチ作ったんです
よかったら食べてくださいね
Oh, yeah! You like
your coffee black, right?
あっ コーヒー
ブラックでいいんですよね？
（火をつける音）
Why don't you say anything?
（ウルフウッド）
なんで 何も言わへんのんや
はい？
Hm?
ガキを殺したことや
About the kid I killed!
あっ…
I don't know what to say.
分かんないです
What you said was right...
牧師さんの言ったことは
正しいし—
...and Mr. Vash was also right.
ヴァッシュさんの言ってたことも
正しいから…
I don't like people to die, but...
人が死ぬのは イヤですけど
What would you have done?
（ウルフウッド）
あんたやったら どないした？
I don't know.
分かりません
わいにも分からへんわ！
I don't know either!!
I don't understand him.
あいつが分からへん
How can he say such things
in this time and place?
こんな時代と環境で—
なんで あいつは
あないなこと言うんや
How can he say such
things seriously?!
それも本気で…
Because that's what
he's always done.
ずっと そうしてたからです
I know because
I've watched him.
私 見てたから分かります
Mr. Vash has lived
his entire life like that.
ヴァッシュさんは ずっと
そうやって生きてきたんです
"Thou Shalt Not Kill!"
“汝(なんじ) 殺すなかれ”だ
What the hell kind of
a churchman are you?!
なんて聖職者だよ まったく
I've lived a different life
than he has.
わいは あいつとは
違う生き方をしてきた
I've been ordered...
依頼されとったんや
...ordered to protect him,
ordered to guide him.
“あいつを守れ”と—
“あいつを導け”と…
But those things
don't matter any more.
そやけどな—
そんなこと
もう どうでもええねん
I honestly wanted to save him...
あのとき 純粋に助けたいと
思うたんや
...even if it meant killing a child,
I wanted to save him.
たとえ ガキを殺してでも
あいつをな
I have to choose one
or the other.
わいには どっちか選ぶしか
あらへんねん
ううっ… おかしいな
It's strange.
Where did I go wrong?
どっかで間違えたとでも
言うんか
I've... I've always chosen
the right path, haven't I?
わいは ずっと正しい道を
選んどったはずやろ…
うっ… くっ
うっ うう…
You smell nice.
あんた ええにおいするな
Please eat the sandwiches.
（ミリィ）サンドイッチ
食べてくださいね
Will you eat them with me?
（ウルフウッド）
一緒に食べてくれるんか？
Milly sure is late.
（メリル･ストライフ）
遅いですわね ミリィ
I don't know.
（ヴァッシュ）
分からないんだ
What should I do?
What should I say?
どうすればいいのか
何を言えばいいのか
Rem...
レム…
（ウルフウッド）
挨拶(あいさつ)もせんと出ていくんか？
Are you leaving
without saying goodbye?
I shouldn't have hit you
the other day. I'm sorry.
この前は殴って悪かったな
堪忍や
That's all right.
いや…
Listen, Wolfwood.
聞いてくれ ウルフウッド
I think it could
have been avoided if...
僕は思うんだ あのとき…
それ以上 言うな！
Not another word!!!
あっ
We live too differently!
生き方が違いすぎる
You and I were destined
to come to this!
わいとお前は
こうなる運命やった
Let's settle the Quick Draw tournament
we started so long ago, here and now!
だいぶ前にやった
クイックドロー対決の決着—
今 つけようか！
But why?!
なぜだ！
言うたら死んでくれるんか？
抜け
If I tell you,
will you die? Draw!
抜け！
DRAW!
（銃声）
やってもいいが
俺の頼みを聞いてくれないか？
All right, but will you
do something in return?
Yeah, what?
何や？
これが終わったら
もう二度と人を撃たないでくれ
When this is over,
don't shoot anyone ever again.
これが終わったら
もう二度と人を撃たないでくれ
When this is over,
don't shoot anyone ever again.
そいで 今のお前のように
撃たれるっちゅうんか？
So I'll become a living target
just like you?
What do you plan
to do about this?!
そしたら この状況
どないするつもりや？
I don't know.
分からない
Answer me one thing!
１つだけ聞かせい
What do you intend to do
once you see Knives?
お前 ナイヴズと会(お)うたら
どないするつもりや？
He stole someone
I loved from me.
あいつは
俺から大切な人を奪った
Do you want revenge?
復讐(ふくしゅう)か？
I don't know.
（ヴァッシュ）分からない
I don't know!
分からないんだ
I see.
So that's how you live.
（ウルフウッド）そうか
そうやって
生きていくんやな
That's how you chose to live.
そういう生き方を
選んだんやな
ホンマに…
You really...
You really piss me off!
ホンマに
ムカつくやっちゃな お前は
Wolfwood?
ウルフウッド…
（弾(たま)をはじく音）
隠れい！
Take cover!
Where's it coming from?!
どっからだ？
It's Caine! He's probably sniping
from the outskirts of town.
ケインや
恐らく 町の外から—
超長距離の精密射撃を
やっとるな
- And he's not alone.
- What?
それに もう１人
（ヴァッシュ）なに！
Caine's yours.
You'll be able to find him.
ケインは任せたで
お前やったら
見つけられるやろ
The other one is mine.
もう１人は任せとけ
"The Stampede"
is a nickname, right?
お前 “スタンピード”って
通り名やろ？
At least tell me
your real name.
ホンマの名前ぐらい教えとけ
Forget it. You plan
to carry it to the grave.
イヤだよ
冥土(めいど)の土産に
持ってくつもりでしょ？
The hell I do. Out with it.
そんなことするかい
言うてみ
Just between you and me...
必要ないだろ
俺たちには
...you don't need to know that.
フッ…
The die has been cast.
Now, down to business.
賽(さい)は投げてしもた さて…
You...
お前…
...no, never mind.
いや もういい
（発砲音）
Mr. Wolfwood?!
（メリル）ウルフウッドさん
I hear gunfire in town...
町中で… あっ
Milly, what are
you doing here?
ミリィ あなた どうして…
I'm staying here, ma'am.
（ミリィ）
先輩 私 ここにいます
He told me to stay here.
“ここにいろ”って
あの人に言われたんです
I'm staying here
until he comes back.
だから あの人が帰ってくるまで
ここにいます
（ヴァッシュ）くっ… こっちか
This way!
あっ
うっ
Liquor?
酒…
He led me in here!
誘われたんか
The lag between shots
and the angles of impact...
ヒントは
発射音のタイムラグと—
弾丸の着弾角度のみ
...gave you away.
It wasn't easy finding you!
見つけんのに難儀したよ
得物も使いもんに
なんなくなったし—
Your gun is kind of broken...
...so why don't you head on home?
It's too hot out here.
そろそろ帰らない？
暑いでしょ？
I'm glad you see it my way.
分かってくれて うれしいよ
あっ
Where?
Where will he attack from?!
（ウルフウッド）どこからや
どこから 来るんや？
うっ
（ウルフウッド）やられる！
He'll get me!!
（ウルフウッド）うあっ
うっ…
ぐっ
（発砲音）
（チャペル）うあっ
ああ…
ハア ハア ハア…
ハア…
What is the best choice?
（ウルフウッド）
最良の選択は何や？
Tell me!!
どうなんや？
ううっ ハア…
Is this good enough?
（ウルフウッド）
これで ええんか？
Is it?!
これで…
（チャペル）うっ…
これが…
This is...
...all I can do.
精いっぱいや
（チャペル）ああ…
（足音）
（ウルフウッド）フッ…
Ah, that felt good!
ああ スッキリしたで
This is a huge disappointment...
とんだ見込み違いだ
I can't believe you wasted
the 10 years I spent on you.
お前と過ごした俺の10年を
ムダにしおって
No, I didn't. I'm using what
you taught me, in my fashion.
そんなことあらへん
あんたに
たたき込まれたこと—
わいなりに使わせてもろたで
May you go with
God's protection.
神のご加護が
あんたと一緒にあらんことを
あっ
ぐっ ああ…
ああ… ぐあっ
（ウルフウッド）うっ
（発砲音）
What's wrong?
（ウルフウッド）どないした？
I failed to save another life.
（ヴァッシュ）
また 助けられなかったよ
Oh, well. Every mortal man
is bound to make a few mistakes.
まあ 人間やったら
１回２回のミスはあるやろ
Just be more careful
the next time.
今度は ちゃんとやり
It isn't something
I can accept that easily!
（ヴァッシュ）そんな簡単に
割り切れるもんじゃない
Then let it get to you.
（ウルフウッド）なら 悩め
That is also
the mortal way of life.
それもまた 人間の生き方や
Mortal...
人間か…
Knives is in Demitrihi.
（ウルフウッド）ナイヴズはな
デミトリッヒにおるで
あっ ナイヴズが？
Knives?
Wolfwood,
how do you know that?
ウルフウッド 君は
どうして そのことを…
I hope you don't
mind me barging in.
（ウルフウッド）
ちょっと…
寄らせてもらうで
うっ…
In spite of my profession,
I've never actually made a confession.
こないな職業に就いとるのに—
わいは 今まで
懺悔(ざんげ)なんかしたことなかった
I justified my actions
by blaming it on the times...
こんな時代や
ガキどもを守ったらなあかん
...saying I did it
to protect the children.
そう思て
自分を正当化させとった
I took many lives,
thinking there was no other way.
しかたない思て
人の命 いくつも奪(うぼ)たんや
フフッ…
My sins are too heavy...
この罪 重すぎるで
...too heavy to ever atone.
償いきれへんほどの重さや
うっ…
Still...
そやけどな—
...I feel really happy
with myself today.
今日は
ごっつ ええ気分なんや
It can be done.
やったらできるやん
Once you stop
to think about it...
誰も死なへん方法なんて—
ちょっと考えたら
ぎょうさんあるやんか
...there are plenty of ways
to save everyone.
Why didn't I see that?
なんで 分からへんかったんやろな
フーッ
That tastes good...
うまいわ…
It's bad for the baby, dear!
おなかの子に さわりますよ
あなた
I'm sorry, honey.
（ウルフウッド）
すまんな マイハニー
If I'm reincarnated...
今度 生まれ変わるんやったら—
...I'd like to live somewhere
where life is easier.
もうちょっと
住みやすいとこがええな
Somewhere with nothing
but peaceful days...
穏やかな生活が続くとこ
...somewhere with
no stealing nor killing...
奪い合いも
殺し合いもないとこ
...Eden.
エデンや
In Eden, I...
そこで わいは… わいは—
...I'll live with him
and the girls, and...
あいつと あの子らと…
ぐっ　あっ ああ…
イヤや 死にたない！
まだ やりたいことあんねん
No! I don't want to die!!
I still have so much to do!
I want to stay...
あいつらと
一緒に… いたいねん
...with them!
うっ…
ぐっ…
Was I?
わいは…
Was I wrong?
Does this mean I was wrong?
あかんのか…
あかん言うんか？
I guess it would be presumptuous
to ask for forgiveness.
許してくれなんて
おこがましいんか
I can't stand it.
かなわんで 実際…
（ミリィの泣き叫ぶ声）
♪〜
〜♪
Repeated tragedy.
Repeated pain.
（ウルフウッド）
繰り返される悲劇
繰り返される痛み
The wishes of man are so strong,
and yet so frail and weak.
人の思いは こんなにも強く
そして はかなくもろい
To live. To stay alive.
生きること
生き続けること—
Who would have known
that survival was this hard?
生き抜くことが こんなにも
つらいものだなんて—
...this painful?
こんなにも
苦しいものだなんて…
僕は 選ばなければならない
I must choose.
I must make the choice.
選択しなければならない
In the moment
intertwining life and death...
生と死が交錯する その刹那(せつな)
...can I choose
to remain a human?
僕は 人であり続けることを
選べるのだろうか？